While most spider and scorpion bites cause only mild reactions like some redness and
swelling, certain venomous ones, like the black widow or brown recluse, can make someone
very ill.
Small children and those with existing medical issues are at a higher risk for more severe
complications, so you'll want to keep a close eye on them.
As you assess the person, watch for signs like muscle cramps, fever, a headache, or
more serious issues like difficulty breathing or fainting.
If you notice severe symptoms like trouble breathing, intense pain, or an altered mental
status, call 911 immediately.
For most situations, your immediate care is to wash the wound with soap and water and
apply an ice pack to manage the discomfort.
For children, it is always a good idea to follow up by calling poison control or their
health care provider for further guidance.
Finally, if you can do so safely and without touching the insect, try to take a photo of
it.
It can be incredibly helpful for medical professionals to identify exactly what caused
the bite and determine the best treatment.